Irene Paulina Moreno

(619)-861-3891 | irenepmoreno@email.arizona.edu

LinkedIn.com/in/IrenePaulinaMoreno

Summary:

Junior with Mechanical Engineering and Mathematics majors Computer Science minor, strong academic standing, and diverse technical experience. Background in Agricultural Engineering industry and Mechatronics Engineering lab. Programming skills including Java, MATLAB and Arduino micro controllers. Bilingual communication proficiency and demonstrated leadership.

Education:

University of Arizona Honors College, Tucson, AZ | GPA 3.12

May 2017

Bachelor of Science in Mechanical Engineering, Bachelor of Science in Mathematics

Minor: Computer Science

Recognition:

- University of Arizona National Merit Scholarship
 - National Hispanic Recognition Scholar, 2012

Credentials:

- Java, Adobe Photoshop, Bridge and Illustrator, SolidWorks, Mastercam, Quickbooks, and MATLAB
- Conversational in Spanish
- Welding, soldering, CNC machines and other power tools
- Tractor, forklift, and other agriculture equipment operation
- Arduino microcontrollers and Arduino programming

Relevant Coursework:

Engineering: Engineering 102, Statics, Dynamics, Elements of Electrical Engineering, Thermodynamics, Intro to CAD, Fluid Mechanics, Behavior of Materials

Mathematics: Calculus 1 & 2, Vector Calculus, Linear Algebra, Analysis of Differential Equations

Programming: Java, MATLAB, Web Programming

Other: Chemistry I, Solid State Chemistry, Mechanics, Electricity and Magnetism

Experience:

University of Arizona AME Department, Tucson, AZ Machine Shop Assistant	2015-present
---	--------------

Assisted machine shop professor in manufacturing of items for the university and senior designs

AME Internship and Training Program, Tucson, AZ | Program Coordinator 2015-present

Coordinated integration program between French foreign exchange students and UA engineering students

University of Arizona AME Department, Tucson, AZ | Lab Manager/TA Spring 2015

Graded and organized material for intro to Mechatronics class. Repaired and organized tools in AME vibrations lab

More-Gun Farms, Caruthers, CA | Intern Summer 2014

Team lead during harvest; repair and maintenance of tractors, forklifts, sprinkler systems and other machinery; managed payroll; utilized bilingual communication skill; assisted in manufacturing of first mechanical overhead vineyard pruner; 60+ hours/week

Rocket Club | Team Lead/Mentor 2013-2014

Served as a mentor for French foreign exchange students and lead building of model rockets

H&R Gunland Ranches, Caruthers, CA | Assistant Welding Manufacturer and Farmhand Winter 2013

Assisted welding manufacturer and gained power tool use skills; assisted in manufacturing of first mechanical overhead vine cutter

Tended grape vines while utilizing bilingual communication skills Summer 2013

Honors and Activities:

University of Arizona Hyperloop Pod Competition Team | Vice-President/Co-Founder Fall 2015

One of five founding members of club; organized and led team meetings; assigned research positions to others and also was a leader of the air bearings/suspension subteam

Raytheon Women in Engineering, Science and Technology Jr. Mentor Program | Mentee Spring 2015

Mentoring program between Raytheon professionals and select University of Arizona students Society of Women Engineers

2013-present

Hosted two girls through outreach program for prospective students.